



Jonas Butt
Senior Cloud-Native Backend Engineer (.NET C# Azure)
28-12-1983 | Amsterdam, Netherlands
jonas@thecodearchitect.com | thecodearchitect.com

Jonas is a Scrum PSD-I certified independent software developer specialized in developing web, cloud and mobile apps built using the Microsoft platform which integrate with Microsoft and non-Microsoft systems, services and technologies. Throughout his 15+ years of experience in software development and consulting Jonas has demonstrated a strong passion for developing well-crafted, reliable, user-friendly software on the Microsoft platform. Jonas continuously improves his programming and software design skills as well as his knowledge of web, cloud and mobile technology and architecture.

From 2008 to 2016 Jonas worked for Avanade as a software developer and consultant on projects that involve developing solutions using Microsoft products and technologies for global enterprise customers. Avanade is a joint-venture between Microsoft and Accenture. Jonas holds a Bachelor of ICT (Computer Science) degree from the Hogeschool voor Economische Studies (HES) in Amsterdam.

In his free time Jonas loves to travel the world with his girlfriend and son, spend time with family, build LEGO sets, watch movies and documentaries, visit festivals with friends and keep up with software technology.

#### Specialties:

- Software Development with .NET Core and C#
- Web Development with ASP.NET Core MVC, Razor, HTML, JavaScript and CSS
- REST API Development with ASP.NET Core
- Database Development with Entity Framework
- Cloud Development with Microsoft Azure and Amazon Web Services
- DevOps and ALM with Azure DevOps and Atlassian
- Software Design and Architecture
- Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Reactive and Software Craftsmanship

#### Characteristics:

- Clean and readable coding
- Both quality driven and pragmatic
- Diligent worker
- Continuous learner and improver
- Easy to work with
- Trust and assertiveness

### Experience

Senior Cloud-Native Backend Engineer (.NET C# Azure) [freelance] at viaBOVAG.nl

2022 - 2023

Working on the subscriptions and payments backend of the Videoland platform.

Technologies used: C#, .NET 7, ASP.NET Core, Azure, Azure DevOps, Blazor Server, Kubernetes, RabbitMQ, MassTransit, MongoDB, Docker, GraphQL, gRPC, Salesforce, PagerDuty among others.

Senior Cloud-Native Backend Engineer (.NET C# Azure) [freelance] at viaBOVAG.nl 2019 – 2022

The mission of viaBOVAG.nl is to be the leading mobility platform of The Netherlands.

As software developer in a Scrum and DevOps team Jonas is involved with all technical aspects of the viaBOVAG.nl platform: coding, software design, user story shaping and estimation, emergent architecture, integrations, technology selection, test automation, code reviews, code quality, build automation, deployment automation, infrastructure automation, operations, hotfixes, stakeholder support etc.

#### Key accomplishments:

- Manage complexity by decomposing a monolith into microservices
- Reduce technical debt by championing technical improvement
- Upgrade to .NET Core 3.1 and .NET 6
- Automate infrastructure and application deployments using a bespoke C#-based deployment framework
- Setup and manage Azure, Azure DevOps and SonarCloud environments
- Migrate the platform between Azure subscriptions and DevOps organizations
- Interview and onboard new developers using custom programming assignment
- Foster knowledge sharing by organizing developer meetings
- Maintain a high quality standard through a vigorous code review process and use of automated tools/linters
- Setup, implement and verify coding guidelines, architecture principles and DoD
- Ensure quality using automated unit, integration and UI testing

All while deploying high quality C# code to production on a daily basis.

Technologies used: C#, .NET 6, .NET Core, ASP.NET Core, Azure (Search, Functions, Web Apps, Blob Storage, Table Storage, CosmosDB, Application Insights, API Management, App Configuration), Azure DevOps, ASP.NET Core MVC among others.

### Senior .NET Developer [freelance] at RDC 2017 – 2018

The mission of viaBOVAG.nl is to create the best platform for BOVAG companies to offer the most reliable used vehicles directly to consumers.

As developer in the Scrum team Jonas was instrumental in all technical aspects of developing this new product from scratch: coding, software design, emergent architecture, technology selection, proof of concepts, QA test automation, code reviews, code quality, build and deployment automation, feature-based development workflow.

Jonas assisted the PO by proposing and shaping user stories, presented new features in the sprint review on a regular basis, was the technical focal point for external partners and represented the team in the architecture chapter.

#### Key accomplishments:

- Design and implement the cloud native backend using Azure, .NET Core and C#
- Design and implement the ASP.NET Core web app
- Design and implement the build and deployment pipelines in Bamboo and Azure DevOps
- Deliver the minimum viable product
- Successfully go live publicly with the first version of the product
- Manage and extend the live product while preventing production issues

Technologies used: C# 7.1, JavaScript, .NET Core, ASP.NET Core, MVC/Razor, Git (GitHub Flow), Microsoft Azure (App Services, Storage, Search, API Management, Functions, Key Vault), VSTS, Azure DevOps, Visual Studio 2017, ReSharper, Swagger/Swashbuckle, Atlassian tooling stack, Slack, Selenium among others.

# Senior .NET Developer [freelance] at funda 2016 – 2017

Jonas is contracted by funda to contribute to their .NET projects. Jonas works on an event-driven microservices architecture used for processing real estate data. Jonas has also contributed to the real estate portals (www.funda.nl, www.fundainbusiness.nl), the real estate agent portal called Funda desk (www.fundadesk.nl). While primarily focused on .NET back-end development Jonas is also involved with backlog refinement, code reviews, QA (testing) and deployments.

Technologies used: C# 7, ASP.NET MVC, .NET Core, ASP.NET Core, AWS SQS, Git (Git Flow, GitHub Flow), SourceTree, Docker, OAuth, Apache Solr, AFAS Connector, NuGet, Artifactory, Bamboo, Bitbucket, Jira, HipChat, Visual Studio 2017, ReSharper, DC/OS, Marathon, Swagger/Swashbuckle, Dapper, Entity Framework, JustSaying Message Bus, SQL Server 2016 among others.

# Independent Software Developer at The Code Architect 2016 – present

Jonas is founder and owner of the Amsterdam based software company The Code Architect. The Code Architect offers software development and consulting services on independent contracting basis (freelance).

# Senior .NET Developer at Transavia 2014 – 2016

This was Jonas' most recent client as consultant for Avanade, where he worked on the e-commerce platform (www.transavia.com) and the API platform (developer.transavia.com). The following two sections describe Jonas' role in these projects.

### Airline API and Integration Platform

Besides designing and implementing features for the Transavia API and Integration platform, Jonas went beyond this role in an effort to improve the maturity of the team and its development process, by:

- Taking the lead in setting up a Definition of Ready, Definition of Done and Definition
  of Released as a vehicle for needed improvements, such user story quality and
  software development processes (CI, CD, peer review).
- Planning and hosting developer meetings to foster knowledge sharing, promote peer reviews and facilitate discussions.
- Documenting and presenting software design principles, which have quickly been adopted and embraced by all developers in the team.
- Working with a software architect from another team to setup continuous integration and a code quality dashboard.
- Taking the lead in the offshoring effort, by defining a developer profile and writing a plan which includes the risks and prerequisites. Jonas also created a programming exercise, reviewed candidate profiles, wrote interview questions and held interviews.
- Work on proof of concepts of innovative ideas, such as actor model programming, Akka.NET and the Reactive Manifesto, and documented and presented the findings to stakeholders (architects, other Scrum teams).

Technologies: .NET, C#, Entity Framework, T-SQL, SQL Server, Navitaire NewSkies SOAP APIs and databases, Apigee, ASP.NET Web API, Swagger, Akka.NET, SignalR, Jenkins CI, SonarQube, SpecFlow among others.

#### Airline F-commerce Platform

As developer in one of the Scrum teams of the Transavia e-commerce platform program, Jonas was responsible for the backend development of various features of the Transavia flight booking website (www.transavia.com) and the My Transavia portal. Features include the payment page, voucher component, travel insurance component and website analytics. Another responsibility

was to integrate the backend code together with frontend code into the Sitecore CMS, setting up the content structure and ensuring features can be easily configured and the content can be managed and localized. For each two-week sprint, Jonas participated in and contributed to sprint planning, backlog refinement, code reviews, sprint review and sprint retrospective. For the monthly releases, Jonas contributed by merging code and resolving defects.

Technologies: ASP.NET MVC with Razor, Navitaire dotREZ framework, Sitecore, Team Development for Sitecore (TDS), Razl, MSTest with SimpleInjector, FakeItEasy and Should among others.

## Consultant and Software Developer at Avanade 2008 – 2016

Jonas was software developer and consultant on projects that involve developing solutions using Microsoft products and technologies for global enterprise customers. Avanade is a joint-venture between Microsoft and Accenture.

Detailed information about Jonas' other projects for Avanade can be found in his full profile.

### Certifications

- SAFe Practitioner, 2022
- MCSD Web Applications, Microsoft, 2015
- Sitecore XP 8.0 Certified Professional Developer, Sitecore, 2015
- Delivery Management at Avanade I, Avanade, 2015
- Professional Scrum Developer I, Scrum.org, 2014
- Avanade Scrum Developer, Avanade, 2014
- MCP Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3, Microsoft, 2013
- Professional Scrum Master I, Scrum.org, 2013
- MCPD Designing and Developing Windows Azure Applications, Microsoft, 2012
- MCTS WCF Development with .NET Framework 4, Microsoft, 2012
- MCTS Accessing Data with .NET Framework 4, Microsoft, 2012

### Education

Bachelor Bedrijfskundige Informatica at Hogeschool van Amsterdam

2005 - 2008

Minor: Software Engineering. Weighted average grade: 8.3

This degree was obtained with honor / cum laude.

Initially the name of the school was HES Hogeschool voor Economische Studies.

- Bachelor Informatiekunde at Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam 2002 – 2004
   This study was not completed.
- VWO Atheneum Economie en Maatschappij at Scholengemeenschap Reigersbos 1996 – 2002

### Languages

- Dutch native speaker
- English near native / fluent